Welcome to the another video, we are going to see another one, uh,
technique and persistence. It's not a degree. It's a procedure.
The account manipulations in previous video, we have successfully created the
account and the tactical T 1136. And, uh,
if you, if you come to the account manipulations, uh,
you can find the tactical T 1098. And, uh, it's in, um,
mitre under the persistence. So the previous video,
we created an account, right? We have created an account, uh,
but we did not set enough privilege, right? So whether the account is
related to the admin privilege or any other privileges, right? So we are
adding the user account, uh, to the, uh, administrator group, okay?
So to list out the, uh, so now you can see my, uh,
now you can see my, uh, who am I all, uh, now I am a user and I am, uh,
I'm in a high mandatory level. So high integrity level. So if you
give net user here, it will list all the user just now we added a user
called, uh, attacker that was added, right? So let's add this attacker to
the administrator group. The attacker will add the, uh, user name to the
several group. There are, there are domain administrator group. So we are
not covering, uh, uh, active directory in this core. So I'm skipping that
domain administrator group domain, adding the user to the domain admin group.
But we will see how to add the user to the administrator group, how
the attacker will add the user to the administrator group, okay? So if you
see the command, so the same, uh, we are abusing the net.exe to add the
user to the, uh, administrator group, okay? So don't need to give the net, uh,
exe net.exe. Let's go to the, uh, if you do find my slash, so I'm a member
of, uh, administrator group and so local account. So let's see, it's a local
group, right? So administrator is a local group of, uh, a machine. And, uh,
and if, which, uh, group you need to add, okay? So if you see here, it's an
administrator group, we need to add the user to the, uh, administrator group.
So let's add to the administrators and, uh, which user name we added, uh, we
added the attacker, right? Attack, uh, it's my user name. Let's add it to the
admin admin group, okay? Maybe I missed to the GROUP or OUP, right? Let's
test this group and the username is attacker and we need to add. That's all,
okay? So net, the similar, uh, local group, uh, which group you need to add,
the administrators group and the username slash shared. So you can,
now you can see the command was, uh, completed successfully, all right? So
now it's added to the, uh, administrator group, the attacker was now, uh,
the attacker privilege was now an administrator, uh, okay. So this how the
threat actor will add the, uh, user to the administrator group, okay? This, uh,
this is called as the, uh, account account manipulation, probably we are
giving the, uh, permission, uh, the administrator group, right? Permission
groups, uh, for, uh, account, right? So here you can find a command, specific
group, uh, right, account, uh, specific group with the net local group. So the
attacker will use the command to, uh, add the user to the admin group or any
other group, okay? So if you need to add the user to the domain group, so it's,
it's a very easy thing. You can give the group. So you can specify the group if,
if, if it's a domain administrator group, you need to find the group first.
So if it's a domain, uh, div, I, I, and domain, uh, admin group, so you can
go ahead and add the domain admin, and, uh, you can give the user name, slash
add, okay? So you can give it like that to add it to the domain admin group,
okay? So this command was not, uh, see this, this command can only used
only a Windows domain controller. So we, we did not have a, uh, domain
controller, uh, eddy, so active directory. So in this course, we are, we are
just covering the Windows side. So we, we, we did not cover the active
directory attacks and all. Maybe next to course, we can see the active directory
attacks. Um, so you, you can, uh, see the net, uh, group. So we need to
specify the group name, you need to add and attacker, uh, the username and just,
it easiest command, right? So this is how the protector will, uh, uh, the
persistence, uh, username and password, uh, for our target environment, okay?
So this is another level of persistence, so adding the shield to us startup
services. That is one set of persistence, and this is another side of
persistence. So attacker need to, uh, maintain their post, maintain their
access to the victim machine. So they will do it like this, okay? So that's
That's all about the video, we will meet you in the next video, thank you for watching.